# 哈喽大家好 我是王刚
Hi guys, it’s Wang Gang
# 本期视频我跟大家分享
Today I’ll share
# 滑肉汤的做法
The recipe of “Tender Pork Soup”
# 首先我们准备前腿肉一块（约300克）
First we prepare a piece of picnic ham (about 300 grams)
# 将肉切成3毫米左右的厚片备用
Cut it to 3 millimeter slices
# 同学们最好选择前腿肉
The picnic ham is the best for the dish
# 这样成菜之后肉不绵比较嫩
The texture is tender enough
# 下一步开始腌制
Then let’s marinate the pork
# 碗中加入食用盐1勺（约1.5克）
Put a teaspoon of salt into the bowl
# 加入少许胡椒粉
Then some pepper
# 加入适量的料酒
Some Chinese cooking wine
# 加入鸡蛋1个搅拌均匀
Add an egg and mix it well
# 加入红薯淀粉1小把搅拌均匀备用（约50克）
Put about 50 grams of sweet potato starch and mix it well
# 同学们搅拌的时候可以适当的摔打
During mixing, toss the pork too
# 然后另外准备一个碗加入适量的红薯淀粉（约250克）
Then get another bowl and put in about 250 grams of starch
# 再加入适量的开水搅拌均匀
Put in some boiling water and stir well
# 同学们这一步必须加入现烧开的开水
The water must be boiling hot
# 拌匀之后倒入装肉的碗中搅拌均匀即可
Then pour the starch into the pork bowl
# 加开水兑红薯粉的目的是增加其粘性
The boiling water will make the starch liquid more sticky
# 这样可以使其下锅的时候不容易脱浆
So it stays on the pork when cooking
# 下一步开始准备辅料
Next let’s get the minor ingredients ready
# 准备丝瓜1条刮掉表皮之后切成滚刀块备用
Peel one loofah. Roll and cut it to pieces
# 不喜欢丝瓜的同学可以用豌豆尖或者绿色的蔬菜
You can also use bean sprouts or other veggies instead
# 再加入适量的红薯粉条备用
Add some sweet potato vermicelli
# 准备生姜1小块拍散备用
Crush a small piece of ginger
# 最后准备小葱几根挽成结备用
Last, get a few green onions and tie them together
# 下一步开始制作
Let’s start cooking
# 锅烧热之后加入少许的植物油
Heat up the wok and put in some vegetable oil
# 油温烧热之后加入几颗青花椒爆锅
When the oil is hot, put the green Sichuan peppercorn in there
# 然后加入准备好的姜葱
Then drop the ginger and green onions
# 略炒之后加入适量的清水开大火烧开
Stir fry and then pour the water in and bring it to boil
# 大火烧开之后将处理好的前腿肉依次下入锅中
When it’s boiling, get the pork in
# 然后再撇去浮沫烧1分钟
Get rid of the scum and then boil for one minute
# 中途加入准备好的丝瓜和红薯粉条
Add the loofah and vermicelli in the meantime
# 烧至1分钟之后再捡去小葱丢弃不用
After a minute, take the green onions off
# 然后开始调味
Next, let’s season the soup
# 锅中加入食用盐2小勺（约5克）
Two spoons of salt
# 加入少许胡椒粉
Some pepper
# 调好味之后即可出锅上菜
After seasoning, it’s ready
# 一道口感爽滑的滑肉汤就制作完成
A “Tender Pork Soup” with smooth and tender texture, done
# 下面开始技术总结
# 第一，最好选择前腿肉或者里脊肉制作，这样成菜更嫩
Now let’s conclude the technical points. First, use the picnic ham or the tenderloin for the juicy texture
第二，挂糊最好用开水调过的红薯粉
Second, mix the starch with boiling water for the pork coat
第三，肉下锅的时候必须保持水开的状态否则容易脱浆
Third, the water must be boiling when we drop the pork. Otherwise the coat will come off
滑肉汤的技术总结完毕
That’s all the points for the “Tender Pork Soup”